PRABIN PRAMANIK

prabin.pramanik@hotmail.com

Data Scientist, +91 7073860185, Noida Sector – 44, Uttar Pradesh 201303, India

Professional Summary

Data scientist with experience of working with Machine Learning, Deep Learning, Natural Language Processing.

Keen interest in data mining, machine learning, predictive modelling, natural language processing. Experience in programming and scripting languages and fluent in working with various CLI platforms – C, C++, MySQL, Python, Java, Linux.

Work Experience

Tidyquant Ltd Data Scientist 1/2018 – 8/2018

- Developed of Hadoop cluster using AWS EC2 instances for ETL process having an ecosystem of Sqoop, HDFS.
- Developed of bank customer churn prediction model to understand the customer's behaviour and identify the certain number of customers those will churn. Using Deep Learning and Azure, Deep Learning instance.
- Developed of time series model to forecast number of visitors to the website in future. Using ARIMA.
- Developed multiple image classification model to identify the object from the image. Using Deep learning.
- Developed recruitment solution project to sort list resumes according to the required skills.
 Using Natural Language Processing and GUI using PyQt5.
- Deployed sentiment analysis model on AWS EC2 using Flask.

Gropse Technology Python Developer 7/2017 – 1/2018

- Developed REST API using Flask, MySQL and project deployment in AWS EC2 instance.
- Developed a website Convertia which converts the document files to the required format, edit videos and download videos from YouTube Using Flask, MySQL and project deployment in AWS EC2 instance.
- Developed REST API using Codeigniter, MySQL and project deployment in AWS EC2 instance.

College Projects 8/2014 – 12/2016

- Developed a website Clear Stack using core PHP, MySQL, JavaScript.
- Developed a web based chat application Instant chat app using core PHP, MySQL, JavaScript.
- Developed basic Java applications Notepad, Calculator, Java P tool.

Skills

Data Science

- Proficient in working with Machine Learning and Deep Learning.
- Ability to visualize datasets using Matplotlib, Seaborn.
- Proficient in working with data frame in a Python environment (Pandas and Numpy).
- Experience in Natural Language Processing projects and large datasets.

Programming and Computer Skills

• C, C++, Java, Python, MySQL, PHP, Linux, OSX

Strengths

- Ability to learn and adapt quickly
- Ability to identify problems and develop solutions
- Ability of storytelling or storyboarding with the help of data visualization tools and techniques
- Strong organizational and interpersonal skills
- Ability to work as an integral member of cross-functional team

Education

2014 - 2017

B. Tech degree in Computer Science

Jaipur National University, India

• 1st class bachelor degree in Computer Science.

2011 - 2014

Diploma degree in Computer Science

Thai Moogambigai Polytechnic College, India

• 1st class diploma degree in Computer Science.